Guide to the New World Writing Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Manuscripts, 1952-1959; Series II; 5.4; (13 boxes)
  - Pasinetti, P. M. "The Incredible Italians", undated (Box 30, Folder 950)
  - Pasternak, Boris. "Il Tratto Di Apelle", undated (Box 30, Folder 951)
  - Payne, Robert. "Dostoevski: The Last Days", undated (Box 30, Folder 952)
  - Paz, Octavio
    - "Night Stroll", undated (Box 30, Folder 953)
    - "A Poet", undated (Box 30, Folder 954)
  - Pétursson, Hannes. "Copernicus", undated (Box 30, Folder 955-956)
  - Picasso, Pablo. "Desire Trapped by the Tail", undated (Box 31, Folder 957)
  - Pinget, Robert. "Mahu or the Matter", undated (Box 31, Folder 958)
  - Piontek, Heinz. "The Blacksmith's Daughter", undated (Box 31, Folder 959)
  - Piovone, Guido. "The Dressmaker's Daughter", undated (Box 31, Folder 960)
  - Plutzik, Hyam. "Jim Desterland", undated (Box 31, Folder 961)
  - Pollock, Jackson. Drawings, undated (Box 31, Folder 962)
  - Pomeroy, Marnie
    - "Grandmother", undated (Box 31, Folder 963)
    - "My House and I", undated (Box 31, Folder 964)
    - "Snow Down South", undated (Box 31, Folder 965)
  - Prévert, Jacques.
    - "At Random: Birds", undated (Box 31, Folder 966)
    - "One Mustn't", undated (Box 31, Folder 967)
    - "To Make the Portrait of a Bird", undated (Box 31, Folder 968)
  - Putnam, Clay. "The Ruined City", undated (Box 31, Folder 969)
  - Rainer, Dachine
    - "Brooding in Summer's House", undated (Box 31, Folder 970)
    - "The Party", undated (Box 31, Folder 971)
  - Rajan, B.
    - "Homecoming", undated (Box 31, Folder 972)
    - "None Shall Escape", undated (Box 31, Folder 973)
  - Rattner, Abraham. Drawings., undated (Box 31, Folder 974)
  - Reed, Henry Hope, Jr. "The Modern Is Dead - Long Live the Modern", undated (Box 31, Folder 975)
  - Reeves, James
    - "And So They Came to Live at Daffodil Water", undated (Box 31, Folder 976)
    - "At the Window", undated (Box 31, Folder 977)
    - "A Homecoming", undated (Box 31, Folder 978)
    - "On a Poet", undated (Box 31, Folder 979)
    - "The Picture in the Mist", undated (Box 31, Folder 980)
    - "The Storm Behind the Hill", undated (Box 31, Folder 981)
    - "Visitors to the Waterfall", undated (Box 31, Folder 982)
  - Reid, Alastair
    - "In Memory of My Uncle Timothy", undated (Box 31, Folder 983)
    - "Oddments, Inklings, Omens, Moments", undated (Box 31, Folder 984)
    - "Visitations", undated (Box 31, Folder 985)
  - Remington, Frederic. "Sketch: A View of Himself", undated (Box 31, Folder 986)
  - Rexroth, Kenneth
    - "Disengagement: The Art of the Beat Generation", undated (Box 31, Folder 987)
    - "Our Home Is in the Rocks", undated (Box 31, Folder 988)
    - "Some Thoughts on Jazz as Music as Revolt, as Mystique", undated (Box 31, Folder 989)
  - Riesmann, Evelyn Thompson. "The Real Train", undated (Box 31, Folder 990)
  - Riuichi, Tamura. "Noontide", undated (Box 31, Folder 991)
  - Rivers, Lucia. "Our Times", undated (Box 31, Folder 992)
  - Robinson, Edna. "The Trouble with the Truth", undated (Box 31, Folder 993)
  - Rodman, Selden. "The Artist Nobody Knows", undated (Box 31, Folder 994)
  - Rodríguez, Félix Pita. "A Friend", undated (Box 31, Folder 995)
  - Roethke, Theodore
    - "Five American Poets", undated (Box 31, Folder 996)
    - "Poems for Children", undated (Box 31, Folder 997)
  - Rolo, Charles James. "Simeon and Spillane: Metaphysics of Murder for the Millions", undated (Box 31, Folder 998)
  - Rousselot, Jean. "Oh Women....", undated (Box 31, Folder 999)
  - Rossi, Jean-Baptiste. "Faces of Hatred and Love", undated (Box 31, Folder 1000)
  - Roy, Claude. "Means of Existence", undated (Box 31, Folder 1001)
  - Rulfo, Juan. "Tell Them Not to Kill Me", undated (Box 31, Folder 1002)
  - Russell, Charles M. (Charles Marion). "Study: Cow Pony", undated (Box 31, Folder 1003)
  - Sabatier, Robert. "The Voyages", undated (Box 31, Folder 1004)
  - Schiller, Marvin. "A Country Weekend", undated (Box 31, Folder 1005)
  - Schmidt, Agusto Frederico. "The Return of the Prodigal Son", undated (Box 31, Folder 1006)
  - Schuyler, James. "Salute", undated (Box 31, Folder 1007)
  - Scott, Tom. "The Mankind Toun", undated (Box 31, Folder 1008)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley
    - "A Calendar of Sante Fe", undated (Box 31, Folder 1009)
    - "Just Before the Hurricane", undated (Box 31, Folder 1010)
  - Seferis, George. "Interval of Joy", undated (Box 32, Folder 1011)
  - Seghers, Pierre. "Life That Passes", undated (Box 32, Folder 1012)
  - Seide, Michael. "The Figure of a Man Falling", undated (Box 32, Folder 1013)
  - Selig, Richard. "Reflection", undated (Box 32, Folder 1014)
  - Selim, Jewad. Drawings, undated (Box 32, Folder 1015)
  - Sellin, Eric. "Seven Contemporary French Poets", undated (Box 32, Folder 1016)
  - Selvon, Samuel. "The Village Washer", undated (Box 32, Folder 1017)
  - Seymour-Smith, Martin. "Blitzenkrieger", undated (Box 32, Folder 1018)
  - Sherman, Sarai. Drawings, undated (Box 32, Folder 1019)
  - Shinpei, Kusano. "Time", undated (Box 32, Folder 1020)
  - Shiro, Murano. "Physique", undated (Box 32, Folder 1021)
  - Siebel, Julia F. "Home Ceremony", undated (Box 32, Folder 1022)
  - Sigurjónsson, Jóhann. "Sorrow", undated (Box 32, Folder 1023)
  - Silone, Ignazio. "Alfredo and the Engineer", undated (Box 32, Folder 1024)
  - Simpson, Louis
    - "Poets of the Silent Generation", undated (Box 32, Folder 1025)
    - "Second American Prelude", undated (Box 32, Folder 1026)
  - Sinclair, Upton. "A Letter to James T. Farrell", undated (Box 32, Folder 1027)
  - Singer, Isaac. "The Mirror", undated (Box 32, Folder 1028)
  - Sitwell, Edith, Dame. "The Road to Thebes", undated (Box 32, Folder 1029)
  - Sitwell, Sacheverell. "Mrs. H or a Lady from Babel", undated (Box 32, Folder 1030)
  - Smith, Sydney Goodsir. "Credo", undated (Box 32, Folder 1031)
  - Smith, William Dale. "The Deserter", undated (Box 32, Folder 1032)
  - Smith, William Jay
    - "Literary Birds", undated (Box 32, Folder 1033)
    - "Three", undated (Box 32, Folder 1034)
  - Smith, Vivian. "Sea Lion", undated (Box 32, Folder 1035)
  - Snodgrass, W. D. (William De Witt) "A Flat One", undated (Box 32, Folder 1036)
  - Solomon, Marvin. "The Peacock", undated (Box 32, Folder 1037)
  - Starkie, Walter. "The First Novelist: Miguel de Cervantes Saavedra", undated (Box 32, Folder 1038)
  - Steiner, Steinn. "Verdun", undated (Box 32, Folder 1039)
  - Steinberg, Saul. Drawings., undated (Box 32, Folder 1040)
  - Steiner, Franz Baermann. "Capturing Elephants", undated (Box 32, Folder 1041)
  - Stevens, Wallace. "Farewell Without a Guitar", undated (Box 32, Folder 1042)
  - Stewart, Desmond. "Four Modern Arabic Poems", undated (Box 32, Folder 1043)
  - Stewart, Robert. "Lament", undated (Box 32, Folder 1044)
  - Summers, Hollis. "How They Chose the Dead", undated (Box 32, Folder 1045)
  - Svafar, Jones. "Radioactive Moons", undated (Box 32, Folder 1046)
  - Swados, Harvey
    - "The Dancer", undated (Box 32, Folder 1047)
    - "Herman's Day", undated (Box 32, Folder 1048)
    - "The Image in the Mirror", undated (Box 32, Folder 1049)
  - Swarthout, Glendon
    - "A Horse For Mrs. Custer", undated (Box 32, Folder 1050)
    - "Ixion", undated (Box 32, Folder 1051)
  - Sweeney, John L.
    - "Exaction", undated (Box 32, Folder 1052)
    - "Separation", undated (Box 32, Folder 1053)
  - Swenson, May. "An Extremity", undated (Box 32, Folder 1054)
  - Sylvester, William. "The Death of San Francisco", undated (Box 32, Folder 1055)
  - Tambimuttu, T. "Poetry", undated (Box 33, Folder 1056)
  - Takal, Peter. "Between the Lines", undated (Box 33, Folder 1057)
  - Terry, J. William. "Dr. Linton Ellsworth", undated (Box 33, Folder 1058)
  - Thomas, Dylan.
    - "After the Fair", undated (Box 33, Folder 1059)
    - "The Followers", undated (Box 33, Folder 1060)
    - "Four Lost Souls", undated (Box 33, Folder 1061)
    - "Seven Letters to Oscar Williams", undated (Box 33, Folder 1062)
    - "The True Story", undated (Box 33, Folder 1063)
  - Thomas, R. S. "The Welsh Hill Country", undated (Box 33, Folder 1064)
  - The Times (London). "Innovation and Tradition", undated (Box 33, Folder 1065)
  - Tommaney, James. "Summer Love Affair", undated (Box 33, Folder 1066)
  - Torri, Julio. "The Hero", undated (Box 33, Folder 1067)
  - Treitel, Ralph. "Jonathan Sam", undated (Box 33, Folder 1068)
  - Trimpi, Wesley. "Letter to Edgar Bowers, November 1954", undated (Box 33, Folder 1069)
  - Trocchi, Alexander. "He Tasted History With a Yellow Tooth", undated (Box 33, Folder 1070)
  - Uhr, Leonard Merrick. "The Jungle Down the Drain", undated (Box 33, Folder 1071)
  - Vaid, Krishna Balder. "Door in the Wall", undated (Box 33, Folder 1072)
  - Van Der Graft, Guillaume. "Hallelujah", undated (Box 33, Folder 1073)
  - Van Loggem, Manuel. "Well Song", undated (Box 33, Folder 1074)
  - Vasalis. Fragment, undated (Box 33, Folder 1075)
  - Vazakas, Byron. "Skating at Versailles", undated (Box 33, Folder 1076)
  - Vennberg, Karl. "Chronometry", undated (Box 33, Folder 1077)
  - Vesaas, Tarjei. "Twenty-one", undated (Box 33, Folder 1078)
  - Vidal, Gore
    - "Erlinda and Mr. Coffin", undated (Box 33, Folder 1079)
    - "Notes on Television", undated (Box 33, Folder 1080)
  - Viereck, Peter. "Algiers in Wartime", undated (Box 33, Folder 1081)
  - Villaurrutia, Xavier. "What Are You Thinking About?", undated (Box 33, Folder 1082)
  - Vittorini, Elio. "A Man and His Son", undated (Box 33, Folder 1083)
  - Von Schlegell, Mary Keep. "Child on a Winter Beach", undated (Box 33, Folder 1084)
  - Von Westphalen, Emilio Adolfo. "I Have Rested My Head Sadly", undated (Box 33, Folder 1085)
  - Vowles, Richard. "Six Modern Swedish Poets", undated (Box 33, Folder 1086)
  - Wagner, Geoffrey Atheling. "The Author and His Editor", undated (Box 33, Folder 1087)
  - Wagoner, David. "Spring Song", undated (Box 33, Folder 1088)
  - Wain, John
    - "Orwell in Perspective", undated (Box 33, Folder 1089)
    - "Remember Stop Milk", undated (Box 33, Folder 1090)
  - Wakefield, Dan. "Salinger and the Search for Love", undated (Box 33, Folder 1091)
  - Walcott, Derek. "Ruins of a Great House", undated (Box 33, Folder 1092)
  - Weales, Gerald Clifford. "The Poet as a Player", undated (Box 33, Folder 1093)
  - Webber, Gordon. "The Kite that Flew Away", undated (Box 33, Folder 1094)
  - Weinstock, Herbert. "Significance in Music: A Plea for Further Investigation", undated (Box 33, Folder 1095)
  - Weiss, Neil. "Late in the Game", undated (Box 33, Folder 1096)
  - Weiss, T.
    - "Domestic Poem I", undated (Box 33, Folder 1097)
    - "Domestic Poem II", undated (Box 33, Folder 1098)
  - Weldon, John Lee. "Sermon", undated (Box 33, Folder 1099)
  - West, Anthony. "The Hedgehog and the Fox", undated (Box 33, Folder 1100)
  - West, John Anthony. "Journey to Moonhowler's Isle", undated (Box 33, Folder 1101)
  - West, Paul. "Albert Camus and the Aesthetic Tradition", undated (Box 33, Folder 1102)
  - Whatmough, Joshua. "One Use of Language: Literature", undated (Box 33, Folder 1103)
  - Whittemore, Reed. "A Brief History of a Little Magazine", undated (Box 33, Folder 1104)
  - Wierzynski, Casimir. "Waking at Night", undated (Box 34, Folder 1105)
  - Wilbur, Richard. "The Misanthrope from Moliere", undated (Box 34, Folder 1106)
  - Wilkins, Eithne. "Person", undated (Box 34, Folder 1107)
  - Williams, William Carlos
    - "Tribute to the Painters", undated (Box 34, Folder 1108)
    - "Work in Progress", undated (Box 34, Folder 1109)
  - Williams, Tennessee. "I Rise in Flames, Cried the Phoenix", undated (Box 34, Folder 1110)
  - Willingham, Calder. "Hamburger for the Cat", undated (Box 34, Folder 1111)
  - Worth, Valerie. "The Climb", undated (Box 34, Folder 1112)
  - Wright, James. "Witches, Waken the Natural World in Spring", undated (Box 34, Folder 1113)
  - Wysong, Robert John. "Look to the Edge", undated (Box 34, Folder 1114)
  - Yasuo, Fujitomi. "Theme", undated (Box 34, Folder 1115)
  - Yong Un, Han. "Inverse Ratio", undated (Box 34, Folder 1116)
  - Young, Marguerite. "My Mother's Evening Guests", undated (Box 34, Folder 1117)
  - Yuk Sa, Lee. "The Summit", undated (Box 34, Folder 1118)
  - Zafar, Sirajuddin. "My Quest", undated (Box 34, Folder 1119)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 34, Folder 1120)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 34, Folder 1121)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 34, Folder 1122)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 34, Folder 1123)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #5), circa 1954 (Box 34, Folder 1124)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #6), circa 1954 (Box 34, Folder 1125)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 34, Folder 1126)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 34, Folder 1127)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 34, Folder 1128)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 34, Folder 1129)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 34, Folder 1130)
  - Miscellaneous (Issue #15), circa 1959 (Box 34, Folder 1131)
- Galley Proofs, 1952-1959; Series III; 1.3; (3 boxes)
  Arranged in order of publication.
  Series III consists of an incomplete set of galley proofs for individual issues of New World Writing.
  - NWW #1 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1952 (Box 35, Folder 1132-1134)
  - NWW #3 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1953 (Box 35, Folder 1135)
  - NWW #5 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1954 (Box 35, Folder 1136-1137)
  - NWW #6 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1954 (Box 35, Folder 1138-1140)
  - NWW #9 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1956 (Box 36, Folder 1141-1142)
  - NWW #10 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1956 (Box 36, Folder 1143-1144)
  - NWW #11 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1957 (Box 36, Folder 1145-1146)
  - NWW #12 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1957 (Box 37, Folder 1147-1150)
  - NWW #14 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1958 (Box 37, Folder 1151-1152)
  - NWW #15 Authors' corrected galleys, circa 1959 (Box 37, Folder 1153-1154)
  - Authors' corrected galleys. William Carlos Williams #8; Tatsuzo Ishikawa #4; Lloyd Frankenberg #1; Modern German Poets Christopher Middleton #13, circa 1952-1958 (Box 37, Folder 1155)
  - Unidentified galleys, undated (Box 37, Folder 1156)
- Editorial and Publicity Files, 1952-1959; Series IV; 3.8; (9 boxes)
  Organized in two subseries: Editorial Files and Publicity Files, which are arranged by issue number.
  Series III is comprised of two distinct but related sets of files consisting of general editorial materials, comments, and promotional materials for New World Writing issues 1 to 15. Those identified as Editorial Files appear to have been created and accumulated primarily by the executive editor, Arabel J. Porter. Those identified as Publicity Files appear to have been created by various individuals, including Hilda Livingston, Maureen McManus, and Jay Towers, working in what was termed the promotion department. Files include interoffice memorandum, incoming and outgoing correspondence, press releases, form letters, contributor lists, payment information, editorial dopesheets, and excerpts of reviews.
  - Editorial Files, 1952-1959
    - NWW #1 General, circa 1952 (Box 38, Folder 1157)
    - NWW #1 Promotion, circa 1952 (Box 38, Folder 1158)
    - NWW #1 Comments, circa 1952 (Box 38, Folder 1159)
    - NWW #2 General, circa 1952 (Box 38, Folder 1160)
    - NWW #2 Promotion, circa 1952 (Box 38, Folder 1161)
    - NWW #2 Comments, circa 1952 (Box 38, Folder 1162)
    - NWW #3 General, circa 1953 (Box 39, Folder 1163)
    - NWW #3 Promotion, circa 1953 (Box 39, Folder 1164)
    - NWW #3 Comments, circa 1953 (Box 39, Folder 1165)
    - NWW #4 General, circa 1953 (Box 39, Folder 1166-1167)
    - NWW #4 Promotion, circa 1953 (Box 39, Folder 1168)
    - NWW #4 Comments, circa 1953 (Box 39, Folder 1169)
    - NWW #5 General, circa 1954 (Box 39, Folder 1170-1171)
    - NWW #5 Promotion, circa 1954 (Box 39, Folder 1172)
    - NWW #5 Commons, circa 1954 (Box 39, Folder 1173)
    - NWW #6 General, circa 1954 (Box 40, Folder 1174)
    - NWW #6 Promotion, circa 1954 (Box 40, Folder 1175)
    - NWW #6 Comments, circa 1954 (Box 40, Folder 1176)
    - NWW #7 General, circa 1955 (Box 40, Folder 1177)
    - NWW #7 Promotion, circa 1955 (Box 40, Folder 1178)
    - NWW #7 Comments, circa 1955 (Box 40, Folder 1179)
    - NWW #8 General, circa 1955 (Box 40, Folder 1180)
    - NWW #8 Promotion, circa 1955 (Box 40, Folder 1181)
    - NWW #8 Comments, circa 1955 (Box 40, Folder 1182)
    - NWW #9 General, circa 1956 (Box 40, Folder 1183)
    - NWW #9 Promotion, circa 1956 (Box 40, Folder 1184)
    - NWW #9 Comments, circa 1956 (Box 40, Folder 1185)
    - NWW #10 General, circa 1956 (Box 41, Folder 1186)
    - NWW #10 Comments, circa 1956 (Box 41, Folder 1187)
    - NWW #10 Promotion, circa 1956 (Box 41, Folder 1188)
    - NWW #11 General, circa 1957 (Box 41, Folder 1189)
    - NWW #11 Promotion, circa 1957 (Box 41, Folder 1190)
    - NWW #11 Comments, circa 1957 (Box 41, Folder 1191)
    - NWW #12 General, circa 1957 (Box 41, Folder 1192)
    - NWW #12 Comments, circa 1957 (Box 41, Folder 1193)
    - NWW #13 General, circa 1958 (Box 42, Folder 1194-1195)
    - NWW #13 Comments, circa 1958 (Box 42, Folder 1196)
    - NWW #14 General, circa 1958 (Box 42, Folder 1197-1198)
    - NWW #14 Promotion, circa 1958 (Box 42, Folder 1199)
    - NWW #14 Comments, circa 1958 (Box 42, Folder 1200)
    - NWW #15 General, circa 1959 (Box 42, Folder 1201-1202)
    - NWW #15 Promotion, circa 1959 (Box 42, Folder 1203)
    - NWW Miscellaneous, circa 1952 (Box 42, Folder 1204)
  - Publicity Files, 1952-1959
    - NWW #2 General, circa 1952 (Box 43, Folder 1205-1206)
    - NWW #3 General, circa 1953 (Box 43, Folder 1207)
    - NWW #3 Special promotion, mailing lists, brochures, circa 1953 (Box 43, Folder 1208-1209)
    - NWW #3 Comments, circa 1953 (Box 43, Folder 1210)
    - NWW #4 General, circa 1953 (Box 44, Folder 1211)
    - NWW #4 Special promotion, mats for reviewers, circa 1953 (Box 44, Folder 1212)
    - NWW #4 Comments, circa 1953 (Box 44, Folder 1213)
    - NWW #5 General, circa 1954 (Box 44, Folder 1214)
    - NWW #5 Special promotion and brochures, circa 1954 (Box 44, Folder 1215)
    - NWW #6 General, circa 1954 (Box 44, Folder 1216)
    - NWW #7 General, circa 1955 (Box 45, Folder 1217)
    - NWW #7 Dylan Thomas - Williams presentation to Harvard, circa 1955 (Box 45, Folder 1218)
    - NWW #8, circa 1955 (Box 45, Folder 1219)
    - NWW #9, circa 1956 (Box 45, Folder 1220)
    - NWW #10, circa 1956 (Box 45, Folder 1221)
    - NWW #11 General, circa 1957 (Box 45, Folder 1222)
    - NWW #12 General, circa 1957 (Box 45, Folder 1223)
    - NWW #12 Comments, circa 1957 (Box 45, Folder 1224)
    - NWW #13 General, circa 1958 (Box 45, Folder 1225)
    - NWW #13 Promotion, circa 1958 (Box 45, Folder 1226)
    - NWW #14 General, circa 1958 (Box 46, Folder 1227)
    - NWW #14 Promotion, circa 1958 (Box 46, Folder 1228)
    - NWW #14 Comments, circa 1958 (Box 46, Folder 1229)
    - NWW #15 General, circa 1959 (Box 46, Folder 1230)
    - NWW #15 Promotion, circa 1959 (Box 46, Folder 1231-1232)
    - NWW #15 Jay Tower file, circa 1959 (Box 46, Folder 1233)
    - NWW #15 Lippincott, circa 1959 (Box 46, Folder 1234)
- General Business Files, 1952-1959; Series V; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Series V. consists of files relating to the general business of publishing New World Writing.
  - Agents, undated (Box 47, Folder 1235)
  - Art, 1953 (Box 47, Folder 1236)
  - Background material, 1952-1957 (Box 47, Folder 1237)
  - British distribution, 1952-1955 (Box 47, Folder 1238-1239)
  - Canadian literature, undated (Box 47, Folder 1240)
  - Contests, 1952-1958 (Box 47, Folder 1241)
  - Contributors (all issues), circa 1952-1959 (Box 47, Folder 1242)
  - Copy editors, 1954-1957 (Box 47, Folder 1243)
  - Copyright, 1952-1957 (Box 47, Folder 1244)
  - Correspondence with magazines, 1954-1959 (Box 47, Folder 1245)
  - Covers, 1956-1957 (Box 47, Folder 1246)
  - Directory of little magazines, 1952-1956 (Box 48, Folder 1247)
  - Daily rejections, 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 1248)
  - Distribution, 1956 (Box 48, Folder 1249)
  - Dutch literature, 1954-1956 (Box 48, Folder 1250)
  - Fellowships, undated (Box 48, Folder 1251)
  - Financial data, 1957-1958 (Box 48, Folder 1252)
  - Foreign language reader. Lanza, Frances, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 1253)
  - Foreign language readers, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 1254)
  - French literature, 1952 (Box 48, Folder 1255)
  - General comments, 1954-1959 (Box 48, Folder 1256-1257)
  - General correspondence, 1953-1958 (Box 48, Folder 1258)
  - General procedure, 1953-1957 (Box 48, Folder 1259)
  - General promotion, 1952-1958 (Box 48, Folder 1260)
  - German writing, 1952-1953 (Box 48, Folder 1261)
  - Icelandic literature, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 1262)
  - Indian New World Writing information, 1952-1955 (Box 49, Folder 1263-1264)
  - Indonesian literature, 1958 (Box 49, Folder 1265)
  - Inquiries, 1953-1956 (Box 49, Folder 1266)
  - Irish poetry and literature, 1954 (Box 49, Folder 1267)
  - Italian literature, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 1268)
  - Japanese literature, 1952-1954 (Box 49, Folder 1269)
  - Magazine Directory (NWW #15), undated (Box 49, Folder 1270)
  - Mexican writers, undated (Box 49, Folder 1271)
  - Miscellaneous, 1953-1958 (Box 49, Folder 1272)
  - Novels and parts of novels submitted, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 1273)
  - Peruvian literature, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 1274)
  - Plays, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 1275)
  - Poetry: General, 1952-1959 (Box 49, Folder 1276)
  - Poets' Theatre, 1954-1955 (Box 49, Folder 1277)
  - Production: General, 1952-1957 (Box 49, Folder 1278)
  - Promotion pieces. All issues, undated (Box 49, Folder 1279)
  - Requests for submissions, 1952-1957 (Box 50, Folder 1280)
  - Rutter, William - Indian authors, 1953-1955 (Box 50, Folder 1281)
  - Russian literature, undated (Box 50, Folder 1282)
  - Scandinavian literature, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 1283)
  - Scoreboard, 1952-1958 (Box 50, Folder 1284)
  - Seven Lively Arts, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 1285)
  - Spanish literature, 1952-1954 (Box 50, Folder 1286)
  - Subscription cards, circa 1958-1959 (Box 50, Folder 1287)
  - Suggestions, 1954-1956 (Box 50, Folder 1288)
  - University of Florida Museum of Creative Writing - Gene Baro, 1953-1954 (Box 50, Folder 1289)
- Clippings and Foreign Reviews Files, 1952-1960; Series VI; 1.3; (3 boxes)
  Arranged by issue number.
  Series VI. consists of foreign and domestic newspaper clippings and tearsheets of reviews of New World Writing from 1952 to 1960.
  - Issue #1 Clippings, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 1290-1291)
  - Issue #1 Extra Reviews, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 1292-1293)
  - Issue #1 Foreign Reviews, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 1294)
  - Issue #2 Clippings, 1952-1953 (Box 51, Folder 1295-1297)
  - Issue #2 Foreign Reveiws, 1952-1953 (Box 51, Folder 1298)
  - Issue #3 Clippings, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 1299)
  - Issue #3 Foreign Reviews, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 1300)
  - Issue #4 Clippings, 1953-1954 (Box 52, Folder 1301)
  - Issue #4 Foreign Reviews, 1953-1954 (Box 52, Folder 1302)
  - Issue #5 Clippings, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 1303)
  - Issue #5 Foreign Reviews, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 1304)
  - Issue #6 Clippings, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 1305-1306)
  - Issue #6 Foreign Reviews, 1955-1957 (Box 52, Folder 1307)
  - Issue #7 Clippings, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 1308)
  - Issue #7 Foreign Reviews, 1955-1956 (Box 52, Folder 1309)
  - Issue #8 Clippings, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 1310)
  - Issue #9 Clippings, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 1311)
  - Issue #9 Foreign Reviews, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 1312)
  - Issue #10 Clippings, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 1313)
  - Issue #10 Foreign Reviews, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 1314)
  - Issue #11 Clippings, 1957 (Box 53, Folder 1315)
  - Issue #12 Clippings, 1957-1958 (Box 53, Folder 1316)
  - Issue #13 Clippings, 1958 (Box 53, Folder 1317)